AKSHAY CHOUGULE

Thane 400601

+919372062963

akshaychougule71@gmail.com

SUMMARY

A skilled SAP ABAP Developer with 4 years of experience in development (2 implementation projects), support, enhancement and optimization coding style and debugging standard SAP programs. Proficient in Odata services, CDS views, 7.4 syntaxes, Function Modules, Classical, ALV and Interactive Reports, proxy, debugging skills (break points, watch points), IDOC's (Inbound, Outbound), BPEM, manual testing, and Transport Request (TR) merges.

SKILLS

- ABAP 7.4 syntax
- IDOCS
- Proxy
- TMG using SAP RAP
- ALV in ABAP
- CDS views
- DDIC

- Function Modules
- BADI/BAPI
- User exits/Customer exits
- Odata services
- Workflows
- ABAP HANA
- Debugging and Troubleshooting

EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate Consultant, 05/2022 - Current *Infosys (Novartis)*

- Created FA (Feasibility Analysis), EE (Effort Estimate) documents as part of development objects
- Created classes for proxies (both inbound and outbound), worked on debugging through SPROXY, and tracked statuses with SXMB_MONI, SRT_MONI, and SRT_UTIL with CPI acting as middleware between \$4 and external systems.
- Developed an OData service-based inventory reclassification tool that performed periodic postings of capitalization and amortization documents based on ledger, dimension, and inventory turnover data. Document reversal and delta uploading were also implemented.
- Created SAP RAP based singleton apps for table maintenance generation
- Performed configuration of AIF setups in AIF/CUST.
- Created tiles and catalogs for standard and custom transaction codes.
- Worked on Implicit enhancements.
- Created report with output for Payment analysis, Payment currency Analysis, Due date analysis and Bank master data analysis.
- Analyzed code and corrected errors to optimize output.
- Recommended improvements to facilitate team and project workflow.
- Gathered business requirements for SAP reporting and functionality enhancements.
- Worked in development team for enhancements and AMS team to resolved the tickets related to idocs, workflows, module pool, smartforms.

Application Development Analyst, 04/2022 - 05/2022 Accenture (EDF Energy)

- Maintained customers that are converted from legacy to smart meters.
- Worked on ALV reports, application server (AL11), MDR programs.
- Maintained all details in respective table for smart customers.
- Synchronized development, testing, quality, and production system.
- Well versed with Transport organizer.
- Identified, debugged and fixed system bottlenecks and problems.
- Performed testing on user defined functions and triggers.
- Directly connect with clients to brainstorm in discussion meetings.
- Trained and coached new hires and junior developers and shared insight into ways to meet tight deadlines and improve overall efficiency.
- Recommended improvements to facilitate team and project workflow.

Application Development Associate, 01/2020 - 03/2022 Accenture (EDF Energy)

- Worked on Function modules based on BOR Object and respective methods to cover the whole Gain/Loss journey of a customer.
- Included fetching data from third-party applications and used it for the registration of customer.
- Included sending data and receiving data to/from Idocs.
- Implemented Function module for respective activity step to handle some functionality at the coding level.
- Error solving using Debugging Skills (Break Points, Watch points).
- Implementation scripts by executing several idoc json's which further reflected in switch document.
- Assisted team members in application design, database design, data loading and schema layout, contributing to achievement of operational and technical project objectives.
- Adopted proactive attitude in seeking out and recommending enhancements to application functionality or proposed solutions to known areas needing improvement.
- Reported complex bugs and technical and performance issues to Team Lead for further investigation and diagnosis of problems beyond scope of expertise.
- Developed and executed unit and integration tests, collaborating with supervisors to achieve valuable test results and apply outcomes to application improvement.

EDUCATION	AND
TRAINING	

Bharati Vidyapeeth College of Engineering, Navi Mumbai, 06/2019 **B.E: Electronics and Telecommunications Engineering** GPA: 7.77

Veermata Jijabai Technological Institute (VJTI), Mumbai, 05/2016 Diploma: Electronics Engineering (74.24%)

ı	Δ	N	C	П	Δ	G	F٩
L	м	ıv	J	u	m	J	EЗ

Marathi, Hindi, English: First Language

English: C2

Proficient

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

https://www.linkedin.com/in/akshay-chougule-8b80691b1/